Register of the Jane Leftwich Curry Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Jane Leftwich Curry collection
1945-2006
2002C66
Hoover Institution Archives
7 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (4.6 linear feet)
Sound recordings and transcripts of interviews, clippings and other printed matter, conference materials, and miscellany, relating to Radio Free Europe broadcasting to Poland, the media in Eastern Europe, and political conditions in Poland, Ukraine and Georgia. Sound use copies of sound recordings available.
Curry, Jane Leftwich, 1948-, collector
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. Use copies of some sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2002.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content Note
The Jane Leftwich Curry Collection consists of Sound recordings of interviews of Polish communist political and media officials, relating to Radio Free Europe broadcasting to Poland, as well as transcripts of interviews with political figures from Georgia and Ukraine. The Subject Files series includes various clippings and articles reflecting the political and economic scene in Poland before and during 1989 political transition.
Collection also contains reports, memoranda, and statistical data relating to public media in Poland. Of particular interest are surveys and studies conducted by Public Opinion Research Center, documenting the impact of media and propaganda on Polish citizens in the late 1980's through the 1990's.
Radio Free Europe.; Audiotapes.; Georgia (Republic)--Politics and government--1991-; Mass media--European, Eastern.; Poland--Politics and government--1945-1980.; Poland--Politics and government--1980-1989.; Radio broadcasting--Poland.; Ukraine--Politics and government--1991-
- Interview transcripts, 2006 October-November and undated (Box 1-2)
  - Georgia, circa 2006 (Folder 1)
    - Bliadze, Lasha (Folder 1: 1)
    - Charkviani, Miranda (Folder 1: 2)
    - Chikovani, Tamar (Folder 1: 3)
      Scope and Contents note
      See also: Sound Recordings of Conducted Interviews
    - Chkhartishvili, Lasha (Folder 1: 4)
    - Djavakhishvili, Gocha (Folder 1: 5)
    - Dolidze, Anna (Folder 1: 6)
    - Gogia, Levan (Folder 1: 7)
    - Gurjalaia, Gocha (Folder 1: 8)
    - Gvanca (Folder 1: 9)
    - Inaridze, Irma (Folder 1: 10)
    - Kakabadze, Gela; Nikolaishvili, Gela; and Zesashvili, Giorgi (Folder 1: 11)
    - Kakabadze, Nana (Folder 1: 12)
    - Kandelaki, Giorgi (Folder 1: 13)
    - Kardava, Tamuna (Folder 1: 14)
    - Karosanidze, Tamar (Folder 1: 15)
    - Khaindrava, Goga (Giorgi) (Folder 1: 16)
    - Khoperia, Eka (Folder 1: 17)
    - Kobalia, Aleksandre (Folder 1: 18)
    - Kolbaia, Vakhtang (Folder 1: 19)
    - Lekishvili, Nana (Folder 1: 20)
    - Lomadze, Maka (Folder 1: 21)
    - Meladze, Georgi (Folder 1: 22)
    - Mikadze, Tamar (Folder 1: 23)
    - Mikeladze, Davit (Folder 1: 24)
    - Minashvili, Akaki (Folder 1: 25)
    - Nachkebia, Badri (Folder 1: 26)
    - Oniani, Goga (Folder 1: 27)
    - Pipia, Irakli (Folder 1: 28)
    - Rostomashvili, Natalia, and Sopiko Samkharadze (Folder 1: 29)
    - Shengelia, Lela, and Malkaz Gvilava (Folder 1: 30)
    - Shengelia, Zaza (Folder 1: 31)
    - Shevardnadze, Eduard (Folder 1: 32)
    - Tavberidze, Zurab (Folder 1: 33)
    - Ttsikhistavi, Nina (Folder 1: 34)
    - Tsuladze, Luka (Folder 1: 35)
    - Turmanidze, Levan (Folder 1: 36)
    - Tutberidze, Tea (Folder 1: 37)
    - Usupashvili, David (Folder 1: 38)
    - Vakhtangidze, Irakly (Folder 1: 39)
  - Ukraine, 2006 October-November (Folder 1-2)
    - Unidentified (Folder 1)
      - Woman dealing with exit polls (Folder 1: 40)
      - "NDI' guy" (Folder 1: 41)
      - "Channel 5 guy" (Folder 1: 42)
      - "Pora man" (Folder 1: 43)
      - Campaign director (Yushchenko block) (Folder 1: 44)
    - Arkhypchuk, Sergii, 2006 November 27 (Folder 1: 45)
    - Babenko, Iuliia (Folder 1: 46)
    - Babinets, Iuryi (Folder 1: 47)
    - Bezverkha, Anastasiia (Folder 1: 48)
    - Bilozir, Oksana (Folder 1: 49)
    - Bondarenko, Kuz (Kuzma?) (Folder 1: 50)
    - Chmelyk, Roman (Folder 1: 51)
    - Chornovil, Taras (Folder 1: 52)
    - Chubarov, Petro, 2006 November 6 (Folder 1: 53)
    - Ditkivska, Kateryna (Folder 1: 54)
    - Horban, Ihor (Folder 1: 55)
    - Horova, Lesia (Oleksandra), 2006 October 29 (Folder 1: 56)
    - Hubska, Viktoriia, 2006 October 25 (Folder 1: 57)
    - Ivanochko, Vasyl (Folder 1: 58)
    - Kachmar, Mariia (Folder 1: 59)
    - Katerynchuk, Mykola, 2006 October 27 (Folder 1: 60)
    - Kobets, Ol'ga (Folder 1: 61)
    - Korkodym, Volodymyr (Folder 1: 62)
    - Kredis, Vitalii, 2006 October 29 (Folder 1: 63)
    - Krystyniak, Oksana (Folder 1: 64)
    - Kryndyk, Ostap, 2006 November 1 (Folder 1: 65)
    - Kulyk, Irina, 2006 November 12 (Folder 1: 66)
    - Lasovsky, Vladyslav, 2006 October 31 (Folder 2: 1)
    - Lukyanenko, Levko, 2006 October 31 (Folder 2: 2)
    - Lytvynenko, Oleksandr, 2006 November 1 (Folder 2: 3)
    - Nebozhenko, Vikto, 2006 November 8 (Folder 2: 4)
    - Pavliuk, Stepan (Folder 2: 5)
    - Petrov, Kyryl, 2006 November 8 (Folder 2: 6)
    - Podgorna, Viktoriaa, 2006 October 28 (Folder 2: 7)
    - Pohrebinskyi, Myhaylo, 2006 October 25 (Folder 2: 8)
    - Ponamarchuk, Dmitri, 2006 November 6 (Folder 2: 9)
    - Rozhniatkovs'kyi, Andrii (Folder 2: 10)
    - Sal'nykov, Sergii (Folder 2: 11)
    - Shevtsov, Andrii (Folder 2: 12)
    - Skrypin, Roman, 2006 November 8 (Folder 2: 13)
    - Soboleva, Tatiana, 2006 November 2 (Folder 2: 14)
    - Sydoruk, Feder, 2006 November 2 (Folder 2: 15)
    - Stets, Iurii (Folder 2: 16)
    - Stetskiv, Taras, 2006 October 31 (Folder 2: 17)
    - Taran, Segiy, 2006 October 30 (Folder 2: 18)
    - Vins'kyi, Yosyp (Folder 2: 19)
    - Voronovych, Mariana, 2006 November 3 (Folder 2: 20)
    - Yusov, Andrey (Folder 2: 21)
    - Zolotari, Yevhen, 2006 October 27 (Folder 2: 22)
- Subject file, 1945-1994 (Box 2-7)
  Includes research centres' reports, RFE reports, articles, and conferences papers related to media in Poland, also political parties brochures, newspaper clippings on political and economic conditions in Poland, Zycie Partii journal articles, publications, and a videocassette
  - Media in Poland, 1970-1993 (Folder 2-3)
    Includes research centers reports, conferences and studies on media in Poland
    - East-West Relations Research Center Symposium, 1970 (Folder 2: 23)
    - Newspapers in Poland, 1990s (Folder 2: 24)
    - Media censorship in Poland, 1980s (Folder 2: 25)
    - Public Opinion Research Center (Folder 2)
      - Media in Poland (Folder 2: 26)
      - Polish TV News vs. RFE News (Folder 2: 27)
    - Surveys on journalism (Folder 2: 28)
    - "Radio and TV Commission" paper by Matt Ilowiecki, 1994 October 25 (Folder 2: 29)
    - East-West Journalists Conference, 1990 October 12-13 (Folder 2: 30)
    - "Restructuring of Television in East and Central Europe," paper for the colloquium of Center for Communication and Information Studies, 1993 October 20-23 (Folder 2: 31)
    - "Civil Society and Media Democratization in East-Central Europe" paper for the Conference on Civil Society, Political Society, and Democracy, 1993 September 16-18 (Folder 2: 32)
    - Western Media (Folder 3: 1)
    - International journalists, 1990 (Folder 3: 2)
    - Radio Free Europe research reports, 1992-1993 (Folder 3: 3)
    - Press Research Center article, 1992 July (Folder 3: 4)
    - "Press," Public Opinion Research Institute Bulletins, 1992-1994 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Political parties materials, 1989-1993 (Folder 3)
    Includes brochures and rosters, pamphlets, minutes of meetings, and articles
    - Communist Party of Soviet Union roster brochure (Folder 3: 6)
    - Senate of the Republic of Poland brochure (Folder 3: 7)
    - Voting sessions in Senate, 1992-1993 (Folder 3: 8)
    - State Council of Poland newspaper clippings, 1980-1986 (Folder 3: 9)
    - State Council Bureau research paper, "Spoleczno-polityczne i Prawne Warunki Pracy Radnych w ich Wlasnej Ocenie" (Folder 3: 10)
    - Articles relating to the political scene in Poland, 1990s (Folder 3: 11)
    - Organizing Committee for 1989 Round Table Negotiations (minutes) (Folder 3)
      - 1989 February (Folder 3: 12)
      - 1989 March (Folder 3: 13)
      - 1989 April (Folder 3: 14)
  - Polish economic conditions materials, 1971-1987 (Folder 4-6)
    Includes clippings, articles, related to political and economic conditions in Poland
    - Administrators on administration, 1980-1985 (Folder 4: 1)
    - Education, 1982-1985 (Folder 4: 2)
    - Employment, 1971-1985 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Employment, salary and pensions, selection of managers, 1978-1985 (Folder 4: 4-5)
    - Health and pharmaceuticals, 1980-1987 (Folder 4: 6)
    - Party, administrative and economic reform, 1981-1987 (Folder 4: 7)
    - Party apparatus position, statistics, 1982-1985 (Folder 4: 8)
    - Structures of control within party, 1981-1987 (Folder 4: 9)
    - European and US economic policy, financial aid, involvement, 1978-1987 (Folder 4: 10)
    - Turnover 1980/81, 1981 December 13 (Folder 4: 11)
    - Economic Crisis: 1956, 1970, 1976. Economic reforms, 1945-1980 (Folder 4: 12)
    - Stories of decision-making, 1977-1987 (Folder 4: 13)
    - Bureaucratic response to criticism, 1983-1986 (Folder 5: 1)
    - Intellectual criticism of policies and decision-making, 1977-1987 (Folder 5: 2)
    - Party elite government criticism of policies and decision-making, 1981-1987 (Folder 5: 3)
    - Public opinion on reforms, system, state institutions, and problems, 1980-1987 (Folder 5: 4-8)
    - Workers' criticism of policies and decision-making, 1981-1985 (Folder 5: 9)
    - Bureaucracy and authority, 1978-1987 (Folder 6: 1)
    - Corruption and misadministration, 1978-1987 (Folder 6: 2-3)
    - Government statements on controlling bureaucracy, 1983-1986 (Folder 6: 4)
    - State programs on overcoming the economic crisis, 1981-1987 (Folder 6: 5)
    - Factories management, managers, self-management, and impact of bureaucracy, 1981-1986 (Folder 6: 6-7)
    - Solidarity groups, 1981 (Folder 6: 8)
    - Solidarity proposals, 1981-1982 (Folder 6: 9)
    - Role of experts, 1978-1985 (Folder 6: 10)
    - Rada Wzajemnej Pomocy Gospodarczej, 1980-1984 (Folder 6: 11)
    - Hungarian reform, 1986-1987 (Folder 6: 12)
    - Other communist countries, 1983-1985 (Folder 6: 13)
  - Journal articles, 1968-1980 (Folder 7)
    Includes articles from Zycie Partii and other journals
    - "Aktualne Problemy Kierowniczej Roli Partii," Zycie Partii No. 6, 1968 (Folder 7: 1)
    - "Kadry Nie Rosna Same," Zycie Partii No. 2, 1971 (Folder 7: 2)
    - "Statutowe Zasady Przyjmowania," Zycie Partii, No. 2, 1972 (Folder 7: 3)
    - "Rozmowy Indywidualne w Partii," Zycie Partii, No. 4, 1977 (Folder 7: 4)
    - "Wsród Pracowników Aparatu," Zycie Partii, No. 4, 1977 (Folder 7: 5)
    - "Tendencje Rozwojowe Lódzkiej Organizacji Partyjnej," Zycie Partii, No. 10, 1977 (Folder 7: 6)
    - "Partyjna Ocena Administracji Gminnej," "Aktywnosc Czlonków Partii w Radach Narodowych i Urzedach," Zycie Partii, No. 2, 1979 (Folder 7: 7)
    - "Doskonalenie Kadr w Urzedach," Zycie Partii, No. 4, 1980 (Folder 7: 8)
    - "Rola Kadr i Polityka Kadrowa PZPR," Zycie Partii, No. 6, 1980 (Folder 7: 9)
    - "W Ocenie Kandydatów," Zycie Partii, No. 9, 1980 (Folder 7: 10)
    - "Istota i Mechanizmy Pracy Partyjnej," Zycie Partii, No. 10, 1980 (Folder 7: 11)
    - "Z Prac Komisji Wnioskowej VI Plenum KC," Zycie Partii, No. 11, 1980 (Folder 7: 12)
    - "Polityka Kadrowa," "Rola Aparatu Partyjnego," Zycie Partii, No. 2, 1981 (Folder 7: 13)
    - "Aby Nie Zmarnowac Szansy," "Dla Dobrego Imienia Partii," "Niewinni Dyrektorzy," Zycie Partii, No. 4, 1981 (Folder 7: 14)
    - "Konieczny Orez," Zycie Partii, No. 6, 1981 (Folder 7: 15)
    - "Nad Przemianami w Aparacie," "Korupcja i Odpowiedzialnosc," Zycie Partii, No. 9, 1981 (Folder 7: 16)
    - Polityka, 1982-1988 (Folder 7: 17)
    - Po Prostu, 1956-1970 (Folder 7: 18)
    - Miscellaneous articles and publications (Folder 7: 19)
    - Articles and publications by Kazimierz Kakol, minister of the Office for Religious Affairs (Folder 7: 20-21)
  - Video. "Azadlyk Means Freedom," "Romania: Searching" DVD, undated (Folder 7: 22)
- Sound Recordings, 2002-2004 (Box 8-9)
  Includes interviews with Polish communist elites about the role of Radio Free Europe in Poland. 82 compact sound cassettes
  - Poland, 2002-2004; 82 sound cassettes (Box 8-9)
    - Interviews' annotations (Box 8)
    - Bozyk, Pawel, interview, 11 July 2002 (Box 8)
      Access
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009247
    - Cechanowicz, Artur, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009252
    - Chanishvili, Nani, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0000238
    - Ciosek, Stanislaw, interview, 21 March 2002 (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009253
    - Czechowicz, Andrzej, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009255
    - Dolidze, Anna, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009245
    - Frelek, Ryszard, interview, 17 March 2002 (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009261
    - Hirovani, Tamara, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009240
    - Jaruzelski, Wojciech, interview, 20 March 2002 (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009262
      The last cassette (parts 3&4), which appears to be from a separate interview on 11 March 2002, is effectively blank.
    - Kania, Stanislaw, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009268
    - Kikalishvili, Davit, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009244
    - Kiszczak, Czeslaw, interview, 07 August 2004 (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009280
    - Klimczak, Wladyslaw, interview, 02 July 2002 (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009281
    - Kozik, Zenobiusz, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009285
    - Kruszewski, Krzysztof, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0000237
      This interview was recorded at 2x normal cassette speed.
    - Kubiak, Hieronim, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009286
    - Kurtz, Andrzej, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009287
    - Kwiatkowski, Stanislaw, interview, 11 August 2004 (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009403
      The interview is in Polish; Curry includes a brief descriptive voice stamp in English.
    - Kakol, Kazimierz, interview, 12 March 2002 (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009269
    - Maciszewski, Jarema, interview (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009407
    - Ramishvili, Levan, and Conquest, Robert, interviews (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009248
    - Lopatka, Adam, interview, 20 March 2002 (Box 8)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009404
    - Conquest, Robert, and Schwartz, Stephen, interviews (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009220
      Part 1: Robert Conquest
      Part 2: Stephen Schwartz
      The audio quality is poor. This is due to the interviews being badly recorded off the telephone.
    - Former Men of Conflict (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009441
    - Irma interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009442
      Irma speaks in another language. A translator conducts the interview between Irma and Curry.
    - Matwin, Wladyslaw, interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0000235
    - Matyniuk, Andrzej, interview, 13 March 2002 (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009419
    - Morawski, Jerzy, interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0000236
    - Natia interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009224
    - Political prisoners interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009225
    - Rakowski, Mieczyslaw, interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009411
    - Sobczak, Joanna, and Strzezewski, Michal, interviews, 30 November 2001 (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009229
    - Sobczak, Joanna, interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009223
    - Starewicz, Artur, interview, 26 January 2004 (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009413
    - Starewicz, Artur, interview, 27 February 2004 (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009414
    - Szacilo, Tadeusz, interview, 18 March 2002 (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009230
    - Szczepanski, Maciej, interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009423
    - Szulczewski, Michal, interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009218
    - Tartarkiewicz, Anna, interview, 31 May 2002 (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009424
    - Tejchma, Józef, interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009427
    - Toeplitz, Krzysztof, interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009234
    - Urban, Jerzy, interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009428
    - Waszczuk, Jerzy, interview (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009429
    - Werblan, Andrzej, interview, 09 July 2002 (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009433
    - Wiatr, Jerzy, interview, 18 March 2002 (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 2002c66_a_0009434
      This interview is about the impact of Radio Free Europe in Poland and on the government.